PROFILE

Results-focused and hardworking Full Stack Developer with experience using a variety of languages and frameworks. Prior experience in a separate environment with managing teams, monitoring performance, training staff, and cultivating stakeholder relations to drive productivity and profitability. Solid understanding of all CS fundamentals.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, WAGZ INC, 2017 - PRESENT

Full time work for a start up in the "Pet Tech" industry. Built and managed companies microservices in Golang and API gateways in node.js. Was fully responsible for the development, coding, and launching of an integrated Amazon Alexa skill for the companies suite of products. Other responsibilities include management of RDS for MySQL, extensive testing of all serverside codebases, and also head of the SysAdmin for the organization.

CONTRACT SOFTWARE ENGINEER, 2018-2019

Contracted for work to support the overall delivery of data quality excellence by profiling existing and new data sets against core data quality metrics, conducting root cause analysis to identify sources of data quality issues/anomalies, and making recommendations for data use.

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, KVSS TECHNOLOGIES 2014-2017

Began assisting owner and CEO of KVSS Technologies over 5 years ago in a part-time role. Transitioned in to a full-time position as of July 2017. Responsibilities include single page application development, unit testing, quality assurance, and development and implementation of new features in a variety of different projects.

SENIOR DATA ANALYST, HAMPSTEAD HOSPITAL, 2011-2017

Supervisory role on a data analytics team in a psychiatric facility. Day-to-day responsibilities include designing and designating tracking sheets and programs to ensure optimal efficiency of each observational period. Tracked observable behaviors through use of Apache. Supervision and support of all staff members as well as training of newly hired staff members.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Developer Nanodegree , Udacity
Intro to Programming Nanodegree, Udacity
React Nanodegree , Udacity
Master's in Human Services - Business, Liberty University
Bachelor of Science in Psychology - Life Coaching, Minor in Business, Liberty University

$S\ K\ I\ L\ L\ S$

Proficient in the programming languages of Golang, Javascript, Python, and SQL database operations. Also possess experience in the use of Typescript, HTML, and CSS. Full proficiency in all branches of the MS Office suite. Official recipient of a 2018 Google Developer Challenge Scholarship.